Dhruv Shah

North York, Toronto, ON 1647) 510-2912 Chruyshah2997d@gmail.com

Software Developer with **5 years** of experience designing, developing, and implementing applications and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. Team player with excellent communication skills, high quality of work, driven and highly self-motivated.

Skills

- Scripting Language: JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, Node.js, Backbone.js, TypeScript, Python.
- **Web**: HTML/HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, JSON Restful, Angular 4, 6, 8, 9, Angular JS, AJAX, Node. JS.
- Methodologies: Agile, Test Driven Development, Waterfall, Agile Scrum
- Database: Oracle, SQL-Server, MySQL, MS SQL, MongoDB.
- IDE: Eclipse, IntelliJ, Spring Tool Suite (STS).
- Testing Tools: JUnit, Mockito, Soap UI.
- Proficient, responsible, and well-versed in MS Project, MS Office Suite, JIRA, Photoshop.
- Completed Python Bootcamp certification course on Udemy.

Work History

Sr. Full-Stack Developer

August 2022 – December 2023

Uppster Logistics Inc, Montreal, Canada

- Involved in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle including requirement, analysis, design, development, testing, release of the project and support.
- Followed agile methodology and involved in daily SCRUM meetings, sprint planning, showcases and retrospective and used JIRA as a tracking tool for the sprints.
- Developed REST controllers using Spring Data REST to serve the UI with required JSON data.
- Created Docker images and ran the Docker containers in various environments
- Used JAVA 8 functional expressions to manipulate the complex user defined data types of Cassandras and developed Microservices.
- Designed dynamic and multi-browser compatible pages using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular Material, Typescript, Angular 11.
- Proficient in developing web applications using Vue.js framework.
- Developed the administrative UI using Angular 8 and Inserted External Style Sheets to various web pages using CSS.
- Performance tuning on JIRA by deleting inactive workflows, screens, field configuration not associated with any project
- Implemented data layer of Spring MVC by using JPA (Java persistence API) used Hibernate as ORM to operate queries on Oracle database.

MultiCIM Technologies Inc, Montreal, Canada

- Worked on a live Health care project to dynamically structure and present stored information.
- Followed Agile methodology throughout the project, involve in Scrum meetings with the team members on day-to-day basis for the update on project status.
- Used Angular 8 and jQuery for the logical implementation part at client side for all the application.
- Extensively used Java 8 features such as lambda expressions, Parallel operations on collections, multithreading and for effective sorting mechanisms and Streams to store and process the data.
- Extremely used plain JavaScript and JQuery, JavaScript Library to do the client-side validations
- Developed dynamic interfaces using JSF, Prime faces, JQuery, Angular 8, Backbone JS and HTML framework based on the user requirements providing structure and consistency throughout the application.
- Developed applications using React while managing the state through Redux and Redux-Forms.
- Built API following RESTful standards to allow users to submit information by storing data in MongoDB.
- Implemented multiple React frameworks to develop complex structures to display relevant information.

Application Engineer

August 2020 - November 2020

Tech-Robo Solutions, Vadodara, India

- Worked on Sapas Telemetics project to track, monitor & display vehicles information.
- Used React JS for Web application, Django for back-end, Nginx and Gunicorn for Build and deployment, bitbucket for git repositories and GitPages for documentation.
- Worked on dev-ops tasks. Contributed to build multiple units, ui and build/deploy plans.
- Mentored 5 interns to help them establish project understanding.

Full Stack Developer

May 2019 - October 2019

Drona & Jigar Enterprises Pvt. Ltd, Vadodara, India

- Devised various custom responsive WordPress sites from design comps that included advanced WordPress features, such as Custom Post Types, Advanced Custom Fields, and WordPress Customize API.
- Developed Contact Us and Booking page in https://rorojammingsproductions.com/.
- Worked as a lead team member and manage user guide to help clients to understand sites features.

Education

2020/09 – 2022/10 Post-graduation diploma: Programming & Web Technologies

L'institut Superieur d'informatique – Montreal, QC

GPA - 3.74/4

2015/08 – 2019/05 Bachelor's Degree: Computer Engineering

Gujarat Technological University - India

CGPA - **8.1/10**